<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Lex’ blog</title>
        <description>Personal blog, by Lex Postma. I blog about Apple, tech, apps, design and sometimes sports.</description>
		<link href="http://blog.lexpostma.me/"/>
		<base href="http://blog.lexpostma.me/"/>
		<image>
            <title>Lex’ blog</title>
            <link href="http://blog.lexpostma.me/"/>
            <url>http://lexpostma.me/img/lex-logo-purple.png</url>
        </image>
        <language>en</language>
		<copyright>Copyright © 2016, Lex Postma</copyright>
        <updated>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 22:46:54 +0200</updated>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 22:46:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
			<item>
				<title>Review: The Dash by Bragi</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/bragi-dash-review</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/bragi-dash-review</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Bragi, a relatively new company based in Munich, Germany, has created <a href="http://www.bragi.com">The Dash</a>, a beautiful set of wireless earphones. The two earpieces are completely wireless from each other and loaded with smarts. They have touch controls, heart rate sensors, an internal 4GB MP3 player, and much more. This is my review of The Dash. I haven’t tested every feature, but I have used them everyday since I received them in late March. These are my experiences with them over the past five months.</p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-apple-watch.png" alt="The Dash with my Apple Watch Sport" />
<figcaption>The Dash with my 42mm Apple Watch Sport</figcaption>


<p>I first saw these earphones on <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/hellobragi/the-dash-wireless-smart-in-ear-headphones">Kickstarter</a> when the campaign had just started, all the way back in February 2014, and wanted them right away. However, I had a little “smart fatigue” and thought it was too good to be true: completely wireless, fitness and heart rate tracking and a headset. I also had my concerns about the 3 hour battery life. Eventually I’d passed on the campaign because of the price: $237 (€210) plus probably another €40 at the border wasn’t really compatible with my student bank account.</p>

<p>Fast forward to January 2016. I got my first full time job, with my first full time salary. I wanted a little “welcome to the good life”-present for myself, and my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B000WAHFBK/?tag=lexpostmame-20">then-current earphones</a> were barely alive. Where others go shopping for clothes, I buy gadgets. So when I rediscovered The Dash from a review, I bought them without any doubts for €299.</p>

<p>At the time, Bragi was still fulfilling their Kickstarter orders, so <a href="https://twitter.com/lexpostma/status/698914429681987586">it took a little while</a> for my package to arrive. But boy was I happy when they arrived.</p>

<h2>The Unboxing</h2>

<p>Holy smokes, opening up The Dash package was the best unboxing experience I’ve ever had. I’ve unboxed many Apple products in my life <a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review1" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review1" title="see footnote" class="footnote">1</a>, but even they can learn something from this.</p>

<p>The Dash arrived in a nice tight box. When you slide the sleeve off, you’re left with a matte black, book-like box that’s soft to the touch. It has one transparent window with The Dash earpieces on display. Opening the box is like reading a book. Page by page the box explains the product to you, showing you more of it’s contents with new windows on every next page. It was really something special. </p>

<p>When you reach the last page, you’re left with just the contents, nicely placed in the box. You have the “FitSleeves” in different sizes, The Dash in their charger, the charger’s cover (“The Slide”) and a nice short but thick Micro-USB cable. </p>

<p>Everything about this product breaths quality. The box had nice thick cardboard pages, the USB cable feels good, The Slide is heavy and sturdy, and the earpieces were kept in place by a solid piece of foam.</p>

<p>All this is from memory by the way. I won’t be making pictures of it, reassembling the box won’t do it justice. But suffice to say, it was awesome.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review2" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review2" title="see footnote" class="footnote">2</a></p>

<h2>The Plugs</h2>

<p>Now about the product itself. The two earpieces fit nicely in my ears. I use the medium FitSleeves, which have the silicone in-ear plugs, but also fit around the entire earpiece, making the whole thing a little bigger and more grippy. Not once did I worry that they might fall out of my ears, and they never have. There are three other sizes, so you can choose which ever fits you best.</p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-fitsleeves.png" alt="FitSleeves in four sizes" />
<figcaption>FitSleeves in four sizes</figcaption>


<p>They’re fairly big for regular in-ear plugs, but incredibly small considering all the components that must be in there. And even though there’s a tiny battery in each plug, their weight is negligible.</p>

<p>When you insert the pieces in your ears, a friendly, sensual, and slightly robotic, female voice starts talking to you. She guides you through the setup and explains the features and settings when you first use them. My mind was blown when I first heard her, what a great user experience.</p>

<p>The bottom part of both earpieces has a touch area to control The Dash, each with its own focus: right is for music, left for fitness. Tap the right piece to play and pause, double and triple tap to skip or skip back between songs, tap and hold for pairing mode, and slide forward and backward for volume control. Side note: The Dash have their own volume control, separate from the iPhone. This might have some advantages, but I wish they could be linked.</p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-duo.png" alt="The left and right Dash earphones" />
<figcaption>The left and right Dash earphones</figcaption>


<p>The left earpiece is for fitness stuff. I haven’t actually used the built-in activity features yet,<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review3" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review3" title="see footnote" class="footnote">3</a> but I might go for a swim with these in the near future. If I do, I’ll report back. What I have used is the heart rate sensor while running, connected with Runkeeper as a separate sensor. It works great and the data gets synced back, so it can be viewed alongside <a href="https://runkeeper.com/user/LexPostma/activity/847577134">the other run data</a>.</p>

<p>When you swipe forward on the right earpiece, you enable ‘transparency mode’. This basically opens up the microphone to outside noise. It’s a good feature, since they’re in-ear models and thus almost completely block any noise. However, it’s a still pretty rude to keep them both inserted while you’re talking to someone, and it’s useless in traffic on a bike because of the wind. </p>

<h2>The Battery</h2>

<p>3 hours of battery life sounds really short. However, it has never been an issue for me because of the charger. The Dash come with a nice solid carrying case, which doubles as the charger. You plug the case in with Micro-USB and snap The Dash magnetically in it, and they’ll be fully charged in 2 hours. But what’s great about it is that the charger itself also contains a battery that will charge these babies on-the-go for up to five full 3-hour charges. </p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-charger.png" alt="The Charger" />
<figcaption>The Charger</figcaption>


<p>I commute by bike and train for 45 minutes twice a day, and I exercise for about an hour three times a week. So in the morning I leave home, plug them in and go to work. Upon arrival I put them in their case. In the evening I plug them in my ears and go home. Then put them back in the case, go eat and after dinner go for a run with The Dash again. At night, I put the case in the charger, together with my MacBook Pro, iPad, iPhone and Apple Watch.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review4" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review4" title="see footnote" class="footnote">4</a> And in the morning everything is ready to go. </p>

<p>The Dash have a color LED to indicate battery life. Blue is full, green high, yellow medium, and red is low. In about 6 months, I’ve only seen the red LED twice.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review5" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review5" title="see footnote" class="footnote">5</a> </p>

<p>With iOS, some devices support showing the little accessoire battery indicator on the Bluetooth icon in the status bar. If I remember correctly, The Dash used to support this, but it doesn’t seem to anymore. Maybe it went away with the security measures Bragi OS 2.0. </p>

<p>Overall the battery is absolutely no issue for me. And the case is great, be it a little thick for a jeans pocket. But it keeps The Dash nicely together so you won’t lose them. </p>

<p>Once you put The Dash in their charger, the LEDs in the earpieces start snoozing. It’s another one of those great little UX touches. It’s like they’re asleep, breathing slowly in and out, like a human being.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review6" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review6" title="see footnote" class="footnote">6</a> What’s more, left and right breath in sync. Such attention to detail! </p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-snoozing.gif" alt="Breathing Dash LEDs" />
<figcaption>Breathing Dash LEDs</figcaption>


<h2>The Sound</h2>

<p>Of course, sounds must come out of these tiny little plugs. I’m no audiophile, but in my opinion they sound really awesome. </p>

<p>I have a long history with headsets: I’ve used many different plugs for regular use and several Sennheisers for fitness. They always broke, and I often went a price tier higher with the next. My dad says I spent way too much money on headphones. He’s probably right.</p>

<p>All this to indicate that I do appreciate a good set of audio plugs to listen to music and podcasts. I have no problems with in-ears, I even prefer them over regular earphones (like the EarPods) because I can hear more bass and they stay better in place for me. And I prefer their portability over on-/over-ear headphones.</p>

<p>So like I said: the sound is really good from these small, battery-powered, fully wireless in-ear plugs. The lows are dark and solid, and the highs are crisp and clear. I have absolutely no complaints about the sound.</p>

<p>Obviously they can’t compete with my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00M1NEUA0/?tag=lexpostmame-20">Bose QuietComfort 25</a>, but that’s for another post. They do win in a (sort of) equal fight against the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00B6ZGSVI/?tag=lexpostmame-20">Jaybird Bluebuds X</a> and the <a href="http://www.apple.com/shop/product/MHAA2AM/A/powerbeats2-earphones-white">Beats Powerbeats2</a>. Both of these are wireless, and both suck in some way.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review7" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review7" title="see footnote" class="footnote">7</a></p>

<p>Also, the audio lag has not been any issue for me, it’s really short. When I press play, the music starts playing almost instantly. Yes, it is noticeable, but not an issue. And because of the way iOS deals with video and Bluetooth headphones, the audio is always in sync with the videos.</p>

<h2>The Wires</h2>

<p>There are none. I repeat, there are no wires. Zero. Nada. And it’s absolutely glorious! I mentioned a few little drawbacks so far, and there are two big ones that really suck, but the lack of wires is not one of those. All my previous headphones broke, almost always at the weakest link: the wire. The Dash are not even wired together. It is Bragi’s biggest feature.</p>

<p>It’s <em>so good</em> the just plug these beauties in, stick your phone in your pocket, and you’re good to go. No cables to worry about, no wires to untangle, no leash behind your head bouncing against your neck while you run, no cords to get stuck behind your saddle when you lock your bicycle, no plugs to get yanked from your ears when you get stuck behind a doorknob.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review8" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review8" title="see footnote" class="footnote">8</a> Just pure freedom and glory. I love it!</p>

<h2>The Downsides</h2>

<p>Though The Dash are pretty and awesome, they do sometimes frustrate me in big ways. There are two major drawbacks that might give you pause. </p>

<h3>Connection issues</h3>

<p>For me the connection range is meh. The range itself is fine. I can place my phone on the dining table in my (small) studio apartment and can hear the music fine when walking around. No issues there. But obstacles really suck, and with obstacles I mean my body. I often get cut off from my music when my iPhone is just in my pocket and I look over my shoulder. </p>

<p>From the Bluetooth antenna in the right earpiece to my right pants pocket is often a struggle when I move my head right. It’s worse on humid days, and with jeans, and impossbile the phone in my left pocket. Apparently there’s too much going on in those 93 centimeters to reliably stream music to my ears. Maybe it’s my iPhone 6s, or the fabric of my pants<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review9" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review9" title="see footnote" class="footnote">9</a>, the belly fat<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review10" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review10" title="see footnote" class="footnote">10</a>, the titanium screw in my shoulder<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review11" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review11" title="see footnote" class="footnote">11</a>, or that I’m 1.95 cm tall. Maybe it’s a faulty Dash antenna, maybe it’s just Bluetooth itself.<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review12" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review12" title="see footnote" class="footnote">12</a> I have no idea what it really is. I do know that it’s pretty annoying to skip beats when you look over your right shoulder. Looking left, which moves the antenna closer, has no issues.</p>


<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-connection.png" alt="Connection issues from my right pocket to my right ear." />
<figcaption>Connection issues from my right pocket to my right ear.</figcaption>


<p>When I go for a run, I always strapped my iPhone to my left upper arm. I’ve had to move it to my right arm to get it closer it the antenna, and it still sometimes skips a beat when I look over my shoulder. </p>

<p>These connection issues really suck. They seem to be worse when listening to music, compared to podcasts. Probably because the higher bitrate in music songs is more demanding of a solid connection. It got a little better with the software update to Bragi OS 2.0, but still not good enough.</p>

<h3>Microphone vs Wind</h3>

<p>The second major issue is with making phone calls, or any use of the microphone whatsoever. Especially outdoors, but also indoors, it sounds terrible. Everyday I ride on my bike between home and work, and for me it’s the best time to call family and friends. But that’s been pretty much impossible with The Dash. The microphone picks up so much wind, that the other side can’t hear a word I’m saying. It’s also why ‘transparency mode’ is useless outdoors. </p>

<p>Indoors it’s okay-ish. I almost never wear them indoors, so I haven’t tried this much. But I just tested it with my girlfriend last night. In our two tests, the microphone differed from sounding good enough to plain robotic. Unfortunalty something (the connection again?) also weakens the <em>incoming</em> sound. So the ringtone sounds stuttery, and the caller starts barely audible and then becomes louder. Still a bad experience. </p>

<p>It’s a real bummer, because Bragi created a pretty fun feature they call Macros. You can nod your head to pick up an incoming call, or shake to reject it. So fun, but the calling feature itself unfortunately leaves too much to be desired. I guess I won’t call my mom from my bike anymore. But hey, did I mention they’re wireless? Yeah, that’s still pretty epic.</p>

<p>These downsides aren’t small, they really mess with the core functionality of a headset. But for me the upsides outweigh the downsides.</p>

<h2>The App</h2>

<p>Bragi has also released an <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/nl/app/bragi/id1038828258?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=1010l9HW&amp;ct=blog">accompanying app</a> on the App Store to control certain settings for The Dash. It’s a very good looking app, and it has all the features nicely displayed. You can enable the Macros,<a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review13" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review13" title="see footnote" class="footnote">13</a> turn transparency mode on and off and change the volume. You can start, sync and review running, cycling and swimming activities. You can also change some smaller settings, edit your profile (used for activity measurements), and it has a built-in manual with tutorial videos. </p>

<figure class="template-for-app-in-iphone">
<img class="app-in-iphone" src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-app-settings.gif" alt="The Dash app settings" />
<img class="iphone-6-template" src="http://lex.test/img/iphone6s-template.png" alt="iPhone 6s" style="display: nonel;" />
</figure>
<figcaption>The Dash app settings</figcaption>


<p>I really like the design of the app. Bragi found a way to override the conventional platform look, but still feel native to it. It looks great, and has all the features you need, though many of which you can luckily also control from the plugs themselves. </p>


<img  style="max-width: 375px;" src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-app-animation.gif" alt="I absolutely love the animation of the centred Dash moving to the top right." />
<figcaption>I absolutely love the animation of the centred Dash moving to the top right.</figcaption>


<h2>Bragi OS</h2>

<p>The Dash actually run their own operating system called Bragi OS. Let me repeat that, these <em>earphones</em> run an OS. And this OS is catching up with all the hardware that it runs on. Bragi filled these plugs with components during the Kickstarter campaign, and they’re gradually starting to enable them with new software releases. Those updates are really easy to do. They do take a few hours, but how weirdly nice is it that your headphones can get better and more features overnight. In mid July they released <a href="http://os.bragi.com">Bragi OS 2.0</a>. The update brought more exercise features leveraging the yet unused sensors, it added more security to the pairing process, it made the sound louder, and more. It’s awesome, and I can’t wait to see what they’ll be adding next. <a href="#fn-bragi-dash-review14" id="fnref-bragi-dash-review14" title="see footnote" class="footnote">14</a></p>

<h2>In The End</h2>

<p>These quality earplugs are truly fantastic sound machines with great UX details and some good smarts. They have removed the last wire I had to deal with on-the-go and they will get better over time with OS upgrades. The convenience and freedom trump everything including their downsides. </p>

<p>I highly recommend <a href="http://www.bragi.com">The Dash by Bragi</a> (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B01BHAU6QO/?tag=lexpostmame-20">Amazon link</a>) for anyone that’s willing to spend a little chunk of cash on wire-free smart earplugs.</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/dash-full-set.png" alt="The complete Dash set" />


<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review1">
<p>Apple products have notoriously great unboxing experiences. I’ve unboxed a lot of Apples over the years, both for myself, but also as part of my job at an <a href="http://resume.lexpostma.me/employment">Apple Authorised Service Provider</a>. Upgrading brand new MacBook Pros, Mac minis and iMacs with more RAM and an SSD can’t be done with the device still in the box. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review1" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review2">
<p>If you really wanna see it, go watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gQTcxO7In08">this video</a> and then come back and read the rest. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review2" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review3">
<p>You can track activities with just The Dash, using all its movement and health sensors. But because I’m a fitness data junkie and I want to keep everything in Runkeeper and lately also HealthKit, I haven’t really used those features on purpose yet. So far Bragi’s tracked fitness data can’t be synced with Runkeeper or HealthKit. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review3" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review4">
<p>No <strong>you</strong> have too many battery-powered devices! &#128517; <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review4" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review5">
<p>Once after running a half marathon, where I commuted to the start with music, and then ran for 2 hours. I was almost at the finish when she said she needed a charge. And once when I’d forgotten to charge the case at night for two days. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review5" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review6">
<p>Just like the little white LED on previous MacBook Pro models slowly started snoozing when you closed the screen. I still find it amazing that you couldn’t see any LED or opening for it when the LED was off. I’ve always loved that feature, and was a little sad that the new MacBook Pros didn’t have the LED anymore. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review6" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review7">
<p>I tried the Jaybird Bluebuds X in July 2013 (that’s what I meant with ‘sort of equal fight’) and loved the freedom of wireless, but hated the fit and sound quality. I returned them within 2 days. In October 2015 I bought Powerbeats2 and returned them within a week because of the bad connection, the big size, and the exaggerated sound. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review7" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review8">
<p>Grrrrr!! &#128545; <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review8" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review9">
<p>When wearing shorts (made from a thinner fabric) it’s less of an issue. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review9" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review10">
<p>It’s not <em>that</em> bad, but I’m working on losing those kilograms. &#128170; <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review10" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review11">
<p>Yeah, I had surgery in my shoulder. Twice. Now there’s a screw there. The tools they used to get it there are epic by the way. But I have no idea if it has any effect on the Bluetooth connection. I think it doesn’t. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review11" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review12">
<p>This is probably it. “The Bluetooth protocol will finally get good with the next version” is what they said with v1.1, and v1.2, and v2.0, and v2.1, and v4.0. The Dash use dual mode Bluetooth 4.0. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review12" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review13">
<p>More Macro options will be extended for <a href="https://developer.bragi.com/">3rd parties</a> at a later date. <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review13" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn-bragi-dash-review14">
<p>In fact, “next” might come real soon. I literally <em>just</em> received an email: “Bragi Has Big News. September 5, 2016” <a href="#fnref-bragi-dash-review14" title="return to article" class="reversefootnote">↩︎</a></p>
</li>

</ol>
</div><hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2016-08-30 08:04:00" pubdate>30
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=08-2016" title="View blog posts from August 2016">August
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2016" title="View blog posts from 2016">2016</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with App" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=app">App</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Gadget" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=gadgets">Gadget</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Kickstarter" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=kickstarter">Kickstarter</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Review" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=review">Review</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Achievements</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/achievements</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/achievements</guid>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 09:41:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/achievements-1-intro.png">

<h2>A quick story upfront</h2>

<p>This week I made something that I thought looked pretty nice. It wasn&#8217;t very difficult for me and the end result was exactly how I wanted it to be. But my family really loved it. I got compliments and high praise from nearly all of them. Now, my family is always pretty complimentary, but this was different. It really meant a lot to them and they couldn&#8217;t have made it themselves and that is why they were so happy that I made it.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m sharing this story, because I found it very interesting to observe this reaction with regards to this project. It gave me a new perspective on what achievements can be. Clearly I achieved something in their eyes, which I didn&#8217;t see as an achievement. And the compliments were lovely but felt a bit out of place. What did I do that made them so proud?</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/achievements-2-achievements.png">

<h2>What are achievements?</h2>

<p>A baby&#8217;s first steps. Winning a basketball game. Finishing a race. Walking 10.000 steps in a day. Eating 10 hard-boiled egg in 1 minute. Climbing the Mt. Everest. Discovering a cure for cancer. Getting a new high score in Threes. Turning 1 year old. Getting to the next level in Angry Birds. A baby&#8217;s first words. Winning a race. Graduating from high school or university. Getting a 9 for a project. Finishing an XL bag of M&amp;M&#8217;s. Getting a 6 for an assignment. Turning 23 years old. Making something that makes people happy. Getting a compliment. Finishing reading a book. Finishing writing a book. Turning 78 years old.</p>

<p>When thinking about achievements, it struck me how different they can be. Things can be achieved on so many different levels. They are dependent on many factors, like age or skill level. A baby&#8217;s first steps are always great, it&#8217;ll be recorded, posted and talked about for weeks. But what about my first steps every single morning, there&#8217;s no mention of that. Let&#8217;s say I&#8217;ve broken my ankle and have been in a wheelchair for 2 months. All of a sudden my new first steps will be talked about again.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s compare these achievements and there assumed reactions.
<ul>
<li>I ran a 1K race and finished (age 10). &#8220;Wow, so great. Congratulations!&#8221;</li>
<li>I ran a 1K race and finished (age 23). &#8220;Mmkay.&#8221;</li>
<li>I ran a 10K race and finished. &#8220;Wow, cool man. How did it go? What was you time?&#8221;</li>
<li>I ran a marathon. &#8220;What!? Wow, that is amazing, congratulations! Which one?&#8221;</li>
<li>I won the New York marathon. &#8220;Hall of Fame! Money. Flowers. Fame. Newspapers. Photos.&#8221;</li>
<li>I&#8217;ve been in a wheelchair for 5 years and ran a 1K race. &#8220;Impossible. Amazing! Tweet. Post. Photos. Tears of happiness.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>Achievements are basically accomplished goals. The more difficult the goal is to reach, the bigger the achievement. And the bigger the achievement, the more likely people want to reward and/or share it. Yet they are also be very personal. I might be really happy with achieving my daily goal of 10.000 steps, while a waitress (someone who walks around all day) might laugh at those 10.000 and a video gamer might think &#8220;couldn&#8217;t care less&#8221;. A professional athlete might want to win a 10K race, while I&#8217;m happy with just finishing it in under 50 minutes and my mom is already proud of me if I finish it at all. However, while I&#8217;m happy with being graded a 6 for an assignment, my mom might want me to get an 8.</p>

<p>What I&#8217;m trying to explain with all these examples is that achievements are made from a few core factors. I think the most important ones are:
- A goal, something to work towards
- The difficulty of reaching that goal
- Your skill level of the activity towards that goal
- Your personal perception or interpretation of these factors
- Someone else&#8217;s perception or interpretation of these factors</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/achievements-3-rewards.png">

<h2>Rewards, compliments and sharing</h2>

<p>So now you have scored 3564 in Threes; You&#8217;ll tweet about it, people read it, done. Your kid speaks his first words; You&#8217;ll record it, post it on Facebook, 103 views, 89 likes, lots of comments and talk about it for weeks. You finished a 10K race for the 5th time; You receive a medal, hang it around your neck until you get home, you&#8217;ll post a selfie, get 15 likes and a compliment from your mom. You get awarded with MVP of the year by your coach; You get a trophy in front of about 80 fellow basketball players from different teams, applause, weeks long recognition, compliments, you get home and place it in a nice visible spot where it will collect dust for years.</p>

<p>There are all kinds of rewards: trophies and medals, retweets, favourites and likes, but also applause, compliments and promotions. And they reward you in different ways. </p>

<p>A trophy is a physical object that you receive from a 3rd party that thinks your achievement is worth this rewarding. Usually this trophy is handed to you in a place where other people are watching, it is made in limited quantity (&plusmn; top 3 spots) and you can give it a (prime) spot in your house so visitors can see it as well. So you get 3rd party recognition, public recognition, a physical reward, long-lasting display and a memory of your achievement.</p>

<p>A &#8220;Facebook Like&#8221; is a completely different reward. It&#8217;s a reaction to a thing you had posted. It is public recognition and a digital reward, but usually does not have long-lasting value. However, it was an achievement that you, yourself, thought was worth sharing, so you wanted to show others that you reached your goal. This is a fundamental, yet interesting, difference from a trophy. You, not a 3rd party, are recognising your own achievement and you want other people to know about it.</p>

<p>And then there is a medal. Of course, there are all kinds of medals, but I&#8217;m looking at the medal you get when you finish a race. Everyone that finished it, gets one. So it&#8217;s not really limited anymore, it is 3rd party recognition (or tradition), a physical reward and a long-lasting reminder. But since you can wear it, the public recognition is something that you can choose. You can wear it for a week and get lots of public recognition, you can not wear it and get no public display. You can hang it in you house, throw it in a box, post a selfie wearing it or make a collage of all your medals. The thing is, a medal is a wearable reward. Wearing it makes you feel proud and good that you reached your goal. It shows others that you are proud and that they might be proud of you as well.</p>

<p>Rewards are a consequence of achievements, intended to appreciate you reaching your goal. They can be small like compliments, big like trophies, or conscious and public like Likes or medals. Every reward is about transferring that appreciation, sharing it. Someone is sharing with you that you did a good job, you are sharing with the world that you reached your goal, your coach is sharing with you how much he values you in front of the whole club, you are sharing with your family that your son can now walk, your family is sharing with you how proud they are of your son&#8217;s steps, your mom is sharing with her colleagues how proud she is with you. Sharing appreciation is at the core of rewarding achievements.</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/achievements-4-intention.png">

<h2>Intention</h2>

<p>In the context of achievements, the medal, as an object, is a reward. It is both personal and public as well as both bold and subtle, depending on how you receive and use the reward. It can be a reminder of the goal you had, a memory to cherish. Or an encouragement towards a new goal. It can be tradition to receive it, or a complete surprise. But above all, it is intended to appreciate you reaching your goal and to the share that with others. </p><hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2014-05-29 09:41:00" pubdate>29
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=05-2014" title="View blog posts from May 2014">May
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2014" title="View blog posts from 2014">2014</a>
        </time><span>, last updated on 29 July 2014</span><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Design" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=design">Design</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“Don’t talk unless you can improve the silence”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/dont-talk-unless-you-can-improve-the-silence</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/dont-talk-unless-you-can-improve-the-silence</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 19:11:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>— Jorge Luis Borges</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2014-04-21 19:11:00" pubdate>21
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=04-2014" title="View blog posts from April 2014">April
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2014" title="View blog posts from 2014">2014</a>
        </time><span>, last updated on 29 July 2014</span><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Comms concept for iOS 8</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/comms-concept-for-ios8</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/comms-concept-for-ios8</guid>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 12:17:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>A unified hub for Messages, of all sorts, FaceTime, and FaceTime Audio</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Nice concept mockup by <a href="https://twitter.com/markmalstrom">Mark Malstrom</a>. Looks great, I want this!</p>

<p><img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/markmalstrom-comm-concept.png" alt="Comm concept" /></p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2014-04-12 12:17:00" pubdate>12
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=04-2014" title="View blog posts from April 2014">April
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2014" title="View blog posts from 2014">2014</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with App" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=app">App</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Concept" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=concept">Concept</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Design" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=design">Design</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with iOS" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=ios">iOS</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="https://medium.com/p/d57751092644" title="Read directly from the source: Comms concept for iOS 8 — Medium">Comms concept for iOS 8 — Medium</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“Time you enjoy wasting, was not wasted”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/time-you-enjoy-wasting</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/time-you-enjoy-wasting</guid>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 13:47:00 +0100</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Great line from John Lennon. I haven't been doing much these last few days, and I really enjoyed it.</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2014-01-30 13:47:00" pubdate>30
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=01-2014" title="View blog posts from January 2014">January
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2014" title="View blog posts from 2014">2014</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Motivational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=motivational">Motivational</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>There are two rules for success...</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/there-are-two-rules-for-success</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/there-are-two-rules-for-success</guid>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 08:25:00 +0100</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Never reveal everything you know</li>
</ol>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2014-01-23 08:25:00" pubdate>23
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=01-2014" title="View blog posts from January 2014">January
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2014" title="View blog posts from 2014">2014</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Humor" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=humor">Humor</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="http://parislemon.com/post/74253714786" title="Read directly from the source: ParisLemon">ParisLemon</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“The most wonderful youth is a youthful mind when you are no longer young”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/the-most-wonderful-youth-is-a-youthful-mind-when-you-are-no-longer-young</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/the-most-wonderful-youth-is-a-youthful-mind-when-you-are-no-longer-young</guid>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 22:04:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Ben Bronsema quoting Paul Leotard at <a href="http://www.tedxdelft.nl">TEDxDelft</a></p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-10-06 22:04:00" pubdate>6
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=10-2013" title="View blog posts from October 2013">October
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“You build a house on where the foundation is, not on where it's not”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/you-build-a-house-on-where-the-foundation-is-not-on-where-its-not</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/you-build-a-house-on-where-the-foundation-is-not-on-where-its-not</guid>
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 22:41:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Great quote from <a href="http://www.io.tudelft.nl/over-de-faculteit/persoonlijke-profielen/docenten/tassoul-m/">Marc Tassoul</a> on people's strengths and weaknesses.</p>

<p>We where designing a game for new multidisciplinary design teams to get to know each other, as a sort of ice breaker. In (design) teams it's always important to known and build on each others strengths.</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-09-07 22:41:00" pubdate>7
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=09-2013" title="View blog posts from September 2013">September
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“Common sense is the least common of all senses”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/common-sense-is-the-least-common-of-all-senses</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/common-sense-is-the-least-common-of-all-senses</guid>
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 22:38:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Important to keep in mind with a lot of things, but with designing in particular.</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-09-07 22:38:00" pubdate>7
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=09-2013" title="View blog posts from September 2013">September
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Wheelchairs basketball</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/wheelchairs-basketball</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/wheelchairs-basketball</guid>
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 22:26:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Really great commercial.</p>

<figure>
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/xwndLOKQTDs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</figure>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-09-07 22:26:00" pubdate>7
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=09-2013" title="View blog posts from September 2013">September
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Commercial" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=commercial">Commercial</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Inspirational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=inspirational">Inspirational</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Sport" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=sport">Sport</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>How it looks and feels is supposed to tell you how it works</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/how-it-looks-and-feels-is-supposed-to-tell-you-how-it-works</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/how-it-looks-and-feels-is-supposed-to-tell-you-how-it-works</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 09:35:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>So we have one arrow at the top pointing down, one at the bottom pointing up, text that &#8216;points&#8217; right and then also a camera which points&#8230; nowhere (and is really small). Tap it, and the lock screen bounces. Hopefully people will divine from that that they can drag the camera up to take photos.</p>

<p> However, that leaves us with three drag indicators at the bottom of the screen, two of which are up! Good luck not triggering the control center when you&#8217;re trying for the camera.</p></blockquote>

<p>When presented with an actual iOS 7 device, my first instinct was to slide UP to unlock, even though I&#8217;ve been sliding left-to-right since 2008. This use-cue is very misleading.</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/ios7-lockscreen.png" /><hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-07-03 09:35:00" pubdate>3
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=07-2013" title="View blog posts from July 2013">July
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Design" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=design">Design</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with iOS" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=ios">iOS</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="http://binarybonsai.com/blog/ios7" title="Read directly from the source: How It Looks And Feels Is Supposed To Tell You How It Works — Michael Heilemann">How It Looks And Feels Is Supposed To Tell You How It Works — Michael Heilemann</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>iOS 7</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/ios7</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/ios7</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 09:22:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Wow! Just wow! The interface looks gorgeous, both the UI and the UX. It will take some getting used to, and yes, your mom and grandpa will call you (if they can find the Phone app), but I'm really looking forward to it. Apple has really kept their promise, and Jony Ive has outdone himself.</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/ios7-screens.png" />

<p>Highlights for me: new today view in Notification Center, NC sync, new multitasking, Control Center and the expanded folders (no longer Games 1, Games 2 and Games 3 folders). Shared Photo Stream is also something the look forward to, since I'm on my way to switching my entire family to iPhone (mom, sis, if your reading this, you two are next).</p>

<p>I had my doubts about the icons but, after a good night sleep, even those are starting to appeal to me.</p>

<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/ios6-vs-ios7-icons.png" />
<figcaption>iOS 6 vs iOS 7 icon comparison, via <a href="http://www.twitter.com/pawsupforu">@pawsupforu</a>.</figcaption><hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-06-11 09:22:00" pubdate>11
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=06-2013" title="View blog posts from June 2013">June
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with iOS" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=ios">iOS</a></span></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>“If you’re tired of starting over, stop giving up”</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/if-youre-tired-of-starting-over-stop-giving-up</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/if-youre-tired-of-starting-over-stop-giving-up</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 22:07:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Motivational quote, originally for running, but applicable to everything basically.</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-06-10 22:07:00" pubdate>10
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=06-2013" title="View blog posts from June 2013">June
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Motivational" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=motivational">Motivational</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/52634387159/motivational-quotes-that-dont-motivate-me" title="Read directly from the source: Motivational Quotes that Don’t Motivate Me | Beyond the Miles">Motivational Quotes that Don’t Motivate Me | Beyond the Miles</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>My Mom’s Computer Keyboard</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/my-moms-computer-keyboard</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/my-moms-computer-keyboard</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 08:25:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://lex.test/img/blog/mom-keyboard.png" /><hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-06-10 08:25:00" pubdate>10
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=06-2013" title="View blog posts from June 2013">June
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Humor" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=humor">Humor</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="http://www.tastefullyoffensive.com/2013/05/moms-computer-keyboard.html" title="Read directly from the source: Tastefully Offensive: Mom's Computer Keyboard">Tastefully Offensive: Mom's Computer Keyboard</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>iOS music concept</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://blog.lexpostma.me/ios-music-concept</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.lexpostma.me/ios-music-concept</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 14:42:00 +0200</pubDate>  
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Really cool and nice looking app concept.</p>
<hr><p class="blogHeaderByline">By <a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&author=lexpostma" title="View blog posts written by Lex Postma">Lex Postma</a> on
        <time datetime="2013-06-04 14:42:00" pubdate>4
            <a class="blend" class="month-year" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=06-2013" title="View blog posts from June 2013">June
            </a><a class="blend" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&date=2013" title="View blog posts from 2013">2013</a>
        </time><span> • Tagged with <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Apple" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=apple">Apple</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Concept" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=concept">Concept</a>, <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Design" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=design">Design</a>, and <a class="blend" title="View blog posts tagged with Music" href="http://blog.lex.test/filter/&tag=music">Music</a></span></p><p class="blogHeaderByline"><b>Originally from <a class="source" href="http://kurocha.blogspot.se/2013/06/ios-music-concept.html" title="Read directly from the source: KUROCHA: iOS Music Concept">KUROCHA: iOS Music Concept</a></b></p>]]></description>
			</item>
    </channel>
</rss>