<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Lex’ portfolio</title>
        <description>Portfolio by Lex Postma. I design things.</description>
		<link href="http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/"></link>
		<base href="http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/"/>
		<image>
            <title>Lex’ portfolio</title>
            <link href="http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/"/>
            <url>http://lexpostma.me/img/lex-logo-purple.png</url>
        </image>
        <language>en</language>
		<copyright>Copyright © 2016, Lex Postma</copyright>
        <updated>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 22:46:54 +0200</updated>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 22:46:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
			<item>
				<title>Drives for OS X</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/osx-drive-icons</link>
				<guid>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/osx-drive-icons</guid>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 11:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<description><![CDATA[<div class="contentBlock">
    <p>A set of 13 drive icons for OS X El Capitan, most of them based on the default hard drive icon. In this day and age, most Macs come with either a SSD or at least a Fusion Drive. I want my icons to display what they represent, so I made a couple that are more accurate than the good ol’ hard drive.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/osx-drive-icons-ssd-hdd.png" alt="Set of 10 icons" />
    <p>There are SSD and HDD versions for Mac and Windows (Boot Camp) drives. </p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/osx-drive-icons-combi.png" alt="Set of 10 icons" />
    <p>A Fusion Drive icon, combining a SSD and the hard drive. A SSD RAID and a HDD RAID, simply stacking the two drives on each other. The colors <a href="/img/portfolio/osx-drive-icons-origin.png">come from</a> respectively Apple’s Fusion Drive marketing, and the RAID Utility icon on OS X.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/osx-drive-icons-backup.png" alt="Set of 10 icons" />
    <p>Then there are three backup drive icons: Time Machine A, B, and C. I’ll write about this someday, but keep in mind, backups are important, which is why I have three different drives, with each its own icon. C is red, because for me that physical drive is <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Passport-Portable-External-Storage-WDBY8L0020BRD-NESN/dp/B009ZEAUJI/">red</a>, and because it’s a <a href="http://bombich.com">cloned drive</a>, not a Time Machine backup.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/osx-drive-icons-extra.png" alt="Set of 10 icons" />
    <p>And finally, three extra drives, which I made because I needed them. A movie drive, an Adobe drive and a Dribbble drive, which was my <a href="https://dribbble.com/shots/2468283-Dribbble-SSD">Dribbble debut</a>. See also my complete set of <a href="/synology-icons">Synology drive icons</a>.</p>
    <p id="downloads"><a class="downloadButton" href="http://lxpst.me/os-x-icons" onclick="ga('send', 'event', 'Portfolio', 'Download', 'OS X drive icon set');">Download my complete OS X drive set</a></p>
</div><hr><ul><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-info-circle"></i><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&category=icon" title="View Icon projects">Icon</a> from
                         <a href="http://lex.test/filter/&year=2015" title="View projects from 2015">2015</a>.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-user"></i>Personal project, because I wanted more glancable, less generic icons for the different mounted drives.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-calendar" title="Thursday, 31 December 2015 at 11:24 Europe/Amsterdam time"></i>Posted on <time datetime="2015-12-31 11:24:00" pubdate>Thursday, 31 December 2015</time>, last updated on 19 January 2016</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-question-circle"></i>Want to know more about Drives for OS X? <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:hello@lexpostma.me?subject=Drives for OS X" title="Email Lex">email me</a>.</span></li></ul>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Synology for OS X</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/synology-icons</link>
				<guid>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/synology-icons</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 23:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<description><![CDATA[<div class="contentBlock">
    <p>A set of 10 icons for Synology network drives mounted on OS X El Capitan. The icons are based on the generic greyish-blue OS X icon from Apple, that is used by default for network drives. I added some details like more LEDs on the front — just like my DS410 has — and custom icons on top.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/synology-icons-defaults.png" alt="Initial defaults Synology icons" />
    <p>Besides a generic Synology one, a home(s) drive and the web folder, there are icons for the default media drives like video, music, and photo. </p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/synology-icons-media.png" alt="Icons for the media drives" />
    <p>But also for a downloads folder, a books folder and software folder. </p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/synology-icons-more.png" alt="Extra non-standard icons" />
    <p>The set is available with and without the Synology text engraved on the top. See also my set of <a href="/osx-drive-icons">OS X drive icons</a>.</p>
    <p id="downloads"><a class="downloadButton" href="http://lxpst.me/synology-icons" onclick="ga('send', 'event', 'Portfolio', 'Download', 'Synology icon set');">Download my complete Synology icon set</a></p>
</div><hr><ul><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-info-circle"></i><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&category=icon" title="View Icon projects">Icon</a> from
                         <a href="http://lex.test/filter/&year=2015" title="View projects from 2015">2015</a>.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-user"></i>Personal project, because I wanted prettier and more descriptive icons for mounted network drives.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-thumbs-up"></i><b>Acknowledgments</b>: Some of the used icons come from the Noun Project, and were created by:

<ul>
<li>Music: <a href="https://thenounproject.com/term/music/928/">Ryan Oksenhorn</a></li>
<li>Software: <a href="https://thenounproject.com/term/app-store/32360/">Simple Icons</a></li>
<li>Homes/Home: <a href="https://thenounproject.com/term/houses/71418/">McKinzie Madsen</a></li>
<li>Photo: <a href="https://thenounproject.com/term/images/22772">Simon Henrotte</a> (altered by me)</li>

<!--
<li>Web: <a href=""></a></li>
<li>Books: <a href="">?</a></li>
<li>Video, downloads: myself</li>
-->

</ul></li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-calendar" title="Wednesday, 30 December 2015 at 23:18 Europe/Amsterdam time"></i>Posted on <time datetime="2015-12-30 23:18:00" pubdate>Wednesday, 30 December 2015</time></li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-question-circle"></i>Want to know more about Synology for OS X? <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:hello@lexpostma.me?subject=Synology for OS X" title="Email Lex">email me</a>.</span></li></ul>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Crystal Slide</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/crystal-slide</link>
				<guid>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/crystal-slide</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<description><![CDATA[<div class="contentBlock">
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-1.png">
    <p>Crystal Slide is a new product for Royal Boon Edam. In essence, it is a completely glass revolving door with no wings. Just a cylindrical shell with a gap rotating inside the outer shell which has two gaps. The big glass cilinder reaches from the floor to the ceiling. Between the cilinder and the storefront is a glass tunnel, creating the effect that customers already seems to be inside. Safety and people flow is ensured by several sensors. </p>
    <video loop autoplay webkit-playsinline>
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-intro-rotation-stakeholders.mp4"  type="video/mp4; codecs=avc1.42E01E,mp4a.40.2">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-intro-rotation-stakeholders.webm" type="video/webm; codecs=vp8,vorbis">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-intro-rotation-stakeholders.ogv"  type="video/ogg; codecs=theora,vorbis">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
    <figcaption>Introduction to Crystal Slide</figcaption>
</div>    
    
<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>Assignment</h2>
    <p>To top my bachelor Industrial Design Engineering, I did this graduation project for Royal Boon Edam, international market leader in terms of entrance solutions. They asked me to design a new entrance for them, to get their foot in the retail business.</p>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2 id="analysis">Company and Market Analysis</h2>
    <p>As a one-week-group, we looked at the company and its history, its identity and vision and the current market it&rsquo;s in. </p>
    <p>&ldquo;Customer focus, innovation, expertise and engagement&rdquo; are the four pillars that Royal Boon Edam identifies as their own strengths. They&rsquo;re on the intersection between architects and contractors which is why they deliver a custom solution to every problem.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-boon-competitors.png">
    <figcaption>Boon Edam&rsquo;s tourniquet and competitor matrix</figcaption>
    <p>We looked at stakeholders, their product portfolio and competitors. And finally we took a look at Boon&rsquo;s future by doing a PEST analysis (Political, Economic, Social and Technological environments), a trend search and a SWOT analysis (Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities and Threats). </p>
    <p>By combining segments from the SWOT analysis we were able to generate interesting search fields. Every group member picked a field that fitted him the most and went continued the assignment individually.</p>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">    
    <h2>Literature Research</h2>
    <p>The entrance of a retail store serves as more than just an a way to enter the building. It&#8217;s about brand experience, the transition from the outside world into the world that is that brand.</p>
    <p>From the analysis and with my personal design challenge, I chose to design a new entrance for Apple Retail Stores, with an appearance comparable to their glass staircases and the 5th Avenue cube entrance in New York.</p>
    
    <h3>Apple Stores</h3>
    <p>I dove in to the context and took a look at Apple Stores worldwide. </p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-apple-stores.png">
    <figcaption>Apple Stores left-to-right: iconic 5th Ave, NY glass cube entrance, Pudong, Shanghai amazing glass cilinder and Amsterdam&rsquo;s classical building</figcaption>
    <p>Since the <a href="http://www.macstories.net/stories/mapping-apples-retail-expansion/">first retail stores</a> in May 2001, Apple has the ability to show their own face behind the products, create a personal bond with its customers and to control the buying experience.</p>
    <blockquote>
        <p>The Apple stores offer an amazing new way to buy a computer. Rather than just hear about megahertz and megabytes, customers can now learn and experience the things they can actually do with a computer, like make movies, burn custom music CDs, and publish their digital photos on a personal website.<br>&mdash; Steve Jobs</p>
    </blockquote>
    <p>Since then Apple has become a big international player in the retail market. With 406 retail stores worldwide and 30 new stores each year they&rsquo;d make a great partner for Boon Edam.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-apple-store-inside.png">
    <figcaption>Apple Store interior with maple wooden furniture, Apple&rsquo;s store layout patent and iconic glass staircase</figcaption>
    <p>They&rsquo;ve created beautiful stores, have a patented lay out and use glass and aluminium combined with maple wooden furniture. Their glass stairs are a true eye-catcher in the stores, designed to <a href="http://www.ifoapplestore.com/apple-store-glass-staircases/">invite customers</a> to the first (or second) floor, which are generally avoided by shoppers. Besides the visually impressive and beautiful design are the stairs with their glass structure a technical and architectural marvels.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-ideas-2.png" alt="Ideation" />
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">    
    <h2 id="concept">Conceptualisation</h2>
    <p>During the concept phase that followed four concepts were developed and modelled from which one was chosen and further developed. This is what became Crystal Slide.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-ideas.png" alt="Ideation and rough sketches" />
    <figcaption>Ideation and rough sketches</figcaption>
    <p>It was this phase that brought the glass tunnel and the glass footbridge to life. The glass tunnel is a way to give customer the perception that their already inside the store. And the bridge is just really awesome to complete the full transparant glass experience.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-early.png" alt="Early sketches and models" />
    <figcaption>Early sketches and 3D models</figcaption>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">    
    <h2 id="embodiment">Detailing and Embodiment</h2>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-5.png">    

    <h3>Material</h3>
    <p>The complete door is made from glass and the outer cilinder is used as the main construction to which all the parts are mounted. The panels are attached with special parts that Apple already developed for it&rsquo;s staircases. The same goes for the glass itself, which is about 5cm thick consistent of three layers.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-user-test.svg" alt="User test results" style="float: right; width: 200px; margin: 0 1rem 0 0;" />

    <h3>User Test</h3>
    <p>The user test showed that people perceive the design as very open and inviting. And by a large percentage it is already matched to Apple in appearance.</p>
    
    <h3>Flow Analysis</h3>
    <p>The door rotates at a variable speed to have optimal open, wait and flow times despite its single opening. It closes at a safe 4.37rpm and as soon as it&rsquo;s closed it&rsquo;ll open at 8.33rpm on the other side. At 75 persons/minute, it has a large capacity thanks to its variable speed and wingless design.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-2.png">
    
    <h3>Safety</h3>
    <p>The door is equipped with several sensors to ensure people&rsquo;s safety. It has unidirectional motion sensors to detect if someone is approaching the door, infrared sensor to prevent injuries if someone sneaks in at the last second and pressure sensors on the edge for when something is stuck between the inner and outer shells.</p>
    <video loop autoplay webkit-playsinline>
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-safety-sensors.mp4"  type="video/mp4; codecs=avc1.42E01E,mp4a.40.2">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-safety-sensors.webm" type="video/webm; codecs=vp8,vorbis">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-safety-sensors.ogv"  type="video/ogg; codecs=theora,vorbis">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
    <figcaption>Safety is ensured with sensors and an extra escape route</figcaption>
    <p>Since the revolving door can&rsquo;t open completely for evacuations, there is a special escape route via the tunnel. There are doors that can close the storefront and when the store is open they&rsquo;re embedded in the glass walls. But in case of emergency, these doors can open up to outside, creation two extra doorways via the side of the tunnel.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-mondoor.png" alt="Mondoor floating doors" style="float: right; width: 200px; margin-left: 1.6rem;" />

    <h3>Working principle</h3>
    <p>To rotate the door inside the cilinder, I&rsquo;ve looked at several options and systems. Eventually I picked a system by Mondoor floating doors.</p>
    <p>Mondoor floating doors use a unique magnetic guidance system, making them silent and very smooth. They&rsquo;re driven by their patented inductive machine inside a closed frame.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-3.png">
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>Added Value</h2>
    <p>Why would Apple want this entrance in their stores? Because it would be a true eye-catcher. The immensely large cilinder will have people stunned and amazed. The glass tunnel and door make it a completely transparant entrance. Its evolutionary operational principal will be a factor of recognition to customer and the door has excellent climate control.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/crystal-slide-4.png">
    <p>This new type of revolving door at this size will be a true experience for customers. People will look up when they&rsquo;re inside it, they&rsquo;ll gaze round when the door revolves around them and they&rsquo;ll look back after their entrance.</p>
    <video loop autoplay webkit-playsinline>
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-pov.mp4"  type="video/mp4; codecs=avc1.42E01E,mp4a.40.2">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-pov.webm" type="video/webm; codecs=vp8,vorbis">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/crystal-slide-pov.ogv"  type="video/ogg; codecs=theora,vorbis">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div><hr><ul><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-info-circle"></i><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&category=product" title="View Product projects">Product</a> for <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=boonedam" title="View projects for Royal Boon Edam">Royal Boon Edam</a></span>, <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=apple" title="View projects for Apple">Apple</a></span>, and <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=tudelft" title="View projects for TU Delft">TU Delft</a></span></span> from
                         <a href="http://lex.test/filter/&year=2013" title="View projects from 2013">2013</a>.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-user"></i>Individual project, delivering a complete picture in 10 full-time weeks, including researching, designing, 3D modelling, documentation and presenting.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-graduation-cap"></i><b>Course</b>: Bachelor Final Project.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-file-text"></i><b>Assignment</b>: How can Royal Boon Edam distinguish itself with a clear proposition for a retailer like Apple where the most optimal entrance experience into Apple Stores is central, but without losing pillars like safety and sustainability?</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-thumbs-up"></i><b>Acknowledgments</b>: <ul>
<li>I got invited to do an internship at Royal Boon Edam.</li>
<li>Was picked to present my project at the introduction lecture for the new batch of students from the year after my year.</li>
</ul></li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-calendar" title="Wednesday, 31 December 2014 at 10:33 Europe/Amsterdam time"></i>Posted on <time datetime="2014-12-31 10:33:00" pubdate>Wednesday, 31 December 2014</time>, last updated on 18 October 2015</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-question-circle"></i>Want to know more about Crystal Slide? <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:hello@lexpostma.me?subject=Crystal Slide" title="Email Lex">email me</a>.</span></li></ul>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Whirlpool Bubble</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/whirlpool-bubble</link>
				<guid>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/whirlpool-bubble</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 18:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<description><![CDATA[<div class="contentBlock">
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-header.png" alt="Whirlpool Bubble" />

    <h2>Say hello to Bubble</h2>
    <p>Whirlpool Bubble is our redesign for the <a href="https://www.whirlpool.co.uk/max,-limited-edition,-blue,-steam,-crisp-%5BMAX-109-MON%5D-100971/858710915470/">Whirlpool MAX 109</a> microwave. We&rsquo;ve conducted a professionally set up user study to test the original microwave and found many usability issues.</p>
    <p>Based of this study, literature research and intermediate surveys, we completely reimagined the user interface to make it easier and clearer to use and made slight alterations to the exterior design to make it friendlier and more ergonomic.</p>
    <p>This redesign was prototyped and subjected to a second user test, which proved to have resolved many of the errors. The final finishing touches were added from this second study which resulted in the Whirlpool Bubble.</p>
    <figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/99039578?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="560" height="316" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure>
    <figcaption>Stop motion concept video of our redesigned Whirlpool Bubble.</figcaption>
</div>    

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2 id="analysis">Research</h2>
    <p>We started with comparing the Whirlpool MAX 109 microwave to similar products and found it to have a very narrow target group and special features that no other microwave has. It&rsquo;s also a very small and compact countertop microwave.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-max-109-on.png" alt="Two active Whirlpool MAX 109 microwaves" />
    <figcaption>Two active Whirlpool MAX 109 microwaves, left is steaming, right is on crisp function.</figcaption>
    <p>From the literature research we concluded, among other things, that a touch interface is not optimal for such microwaves.</p>

    <h3>1st User Study</h3>
    <p>Then we did our first user study to test the product with users and to see which problems occur. </p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-setup.png" alt="User study setup" />
    <figcaption>The user study setup and a peek in the camera room</figcaption>
    <p>We concluded the problems on a higher level:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>The <em>perception</em> of the user is <em>different</em> to what is <em>actually happening</em>.</li>
        <li>The user interface does not <em>guide</em> the user in its <em>hierarchy</em> and <em>communication</em>.</li>
        <li>The user interface is <em>inconsistent</em>.</li>
        <li>Users easily gets lost in the <em>sequence</em>.</li>
    </ul>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-max-109-issues.png" alt="Interface issues" />
    <figcaption>Interface issues with the Whirlpool microwave, highlighted by the 1st user study.</figcaption>
    <p>We defined our design goal as follows:</p>
    <blockquote>
    <p>The microwave should <em>communicate</em> with <em>clarity</em> to the user and be <em>reliable</em> in its use.</p>
    </blockquote>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">    
    <h2 id="concept">Concepts</h2>
    <p>We started designing and after several concepts, we came up with a completely new interface. The new design has just three buttons and big rounded display. The screen has five bubbles representing the options, each with an icon and name. The biggest button can be used to scroll through the circles and select one. The selected bubble slides to the left and new, underlying options appear. The circles on the left portray a settings-timeline. The available options-structure is based on a new flowchart that was developed to improve the flow, and simplify the steps.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-concepts.png" alt="Redesigning the interface" />
    <figcaption>Redesigning the interface by brainstorm, drawing and making mock-ups.</figcaption>
    <p>We&rsquo;ve done extra research to elaborate more on the wattage selection. From our survey, we concluded that people feel most secure when selecting a wattage when it is abstracted and explained. We pioneered a new way of setting the wattage by combining a visual representation with the wattage values and explanatory words.</p>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2 id="embodiment">Redesign and 2nd User Study</h2>    
    <p>Then we built a prototype, which gave us the chance to test our redesign with a second user study. The results from study two were mainly about refinements as the redesign was generally liked.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-prototype.png" alt="Prototype" />
    <figcaption>The prototype of our redesign.</figcaption>
    <p>We&rsquo;ve restructured some functions again and improved the wattage selection even further. We&rsquo;ve also removed causes for insecurity like setting a time value by going back to the Whirlpool MAX 109&rsquo;s original 6th Sense food options.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-interface.png" alt="New interface" />
    <figcaption>The new interface.</figcaption>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-redesign.png" alt="New interface" />
    <figcaption>The new interface on the Whirlpool Bubble.</figcaption>
    <p>You can also see the all the <a href="/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-icons.png">icons</a> we designed for the new interface. And these are the flows through the screens the the different functions: <a href="/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-flow-microwave.png">microwave</a>, <a href="/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-flow-grill.png">grill</a>, <a href="/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-flow-combigrill.png">combi grill</a> and <a href="/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-flow-steam.png">steam</a></p>
    <p>We also removed a button, resulting in just two buttons: a back-button and a scrolling confirm-button.</p>
    <p>We can conclude that we met our design goal, as we included a questionnaire in our second study. The participants scored our redesign with an average of 5.8 out of 7 for clarity, 5.3 out of 7 for reliability and 5.8 out of 7 for satisfaction.</p>
    <p>Our final design has a titled front to make the aesthetics friendlier and improve readability.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/whirlpool-bubble-side.png" alt="Redesigned Whirlpool Bubble" />
</div><hr><ul><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-info-circle"></i><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&category=product" title="View Product projects">Product</a> for <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=whirlpool" title="View projects for Whirlpool">Whirlpool</a></span>, and <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=tudelft" title="View projects for TU Delft">TU Delft</a></span></span> from
                         <a href="http://lex.test/filter/&year=2014" title="View projects from 2014">2014</a>.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-users"></i>Team effort with fellow creators <span class="ownName"><a title="Nai-Dan Chang’s LinkedIn" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/nai-dan-chang/7b/328/8ab/">Nai-Dan Chang</a></span>, <span class="ownName"><a title="Emma van Dam’s LinkedIn" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/emma-van-dam/95/4a1/473">Emma van Dam</a></span>, <span class="ownName"><a title="Telmen Dzjind’s website" class="creator" href="http://www.studiohikari.nl">Telmen Dzjind</a></span>, and <span class="ownName"><a title="Calliope Savvaki’s LinkedIn" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/calliope-savvaki/51/380/b7a">Calliope Savvaki</a></span>. In this team I participated in all aspects, including conceptualising, prototyping, testing and designing the new interface and documenting the final report.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-graduation-cap"></i><b>Course</b>: Usability and User eXperience Assessment in Design.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-file-text"></i><b>Assignment</b>: Redesign the <a href="https://www.whirlpool.co.uk/max,-limited-edition,-blue,-steam,-crisp-%5BMAX-109-MON%5D-100971/858710915470/">Whirlpool MAX 109</a> to improve its usability.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-calendar" title="Monday, 15 December 2014 at 18:36 Europe/Amsterdam time"></i>Posted on <time datetime="2014-12-15 18:36:00" pubdate>Monday, 15 December 2014</time></li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-question-circle"></i>Want to know more about Whirlpool Bubble? <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:hello@lexpostma.me?subject=Whirlpool Bubble" title="Email Lex">email me</a>.</span></li></ul>]]></description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>Shaped</title>
				<author>Lex Postma</author>
				<link>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/shaped</link>
				<guid>http://portfolio.lexpostma.me/shaped</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 13:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<description><![CDATA[<div class="contentBlock">
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-header.png" alt="Shaped header" />
    <h2 id="concept">Put on your running shoes and get in shape</h2>
    <p>Shaped let&rsquo;s you run a route of a specific shape with runners all around the world. You tell the app how long or how far you plan to run and it will suggest shapes to you. You select a shape and the app will calculate the best route through the streets near your location based on your location, preferences and previous workouts. Once you start running it will navigate you through those streets, forming (part of) a shape on the map.</p>
    <p>You can collaborate on a shape with your friends, people in your local area or even globally. You can see what shapes your friends ran and join them. Or you could invite them to the shapes you&rsquo;re running.</p>
    <p>The routes do not have to be connected, they will be combined in the app. This way, <em>you</em> might run the left ear of a bunny shape, while someone in New York can run the teeth of that bunny and the right cheek is run in London. Or you can run one page each day and the app combines those pages to a book once you&rsquo;re done.</p>

    <figure>
        <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/86708338?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="1920" height="1080" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </figure>
    <figcaption>Concept video of Shaped as shown at the final presentation. Shot and edited in one night.</figcaption>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>Design Goal and Interaction Vision</h2>
    <p>My goal in this project was to savor a good run. My string of thought was such that, when you have more fun and work on something together, you have more to look back at afterwards. And not only more, but also a better memory of it.</p>
    <p>There&rsquo;s a Dutch tradition where on several evenings, prior to Sinterklaas pakjesavond, children place their shoes near the fireplace. They fill the shoe with drawings, wish lists and a little something for Sinterklaas&rsquo; horse (which explains the carrots). After singing Sinterklaas songs they go to bed. The next morning the drawings and carrots are replaced with kruidnoten, sometimes poems and of course a present.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-interaction-vision.png" alt="Interaction Vision" />
    <figcaption>Interaction Vision metaphor</figcaption>
    <p>This interaction contains many great qualities, like preparation, anticipation, stimulation and fun. It&rsquo;s a social event where children and parents sit and sing together, yet also personal where every family has their own way of doing things. The presents the children get the next morning are rewards for singing the night before and for being sweet kids.</p>
    <p>I used this ritual as a metaphor for the interaction with Shaped. It is <em>fun, social, stimulating</em> and <em>rewarding</em>. Using Shaped and running those shaped routes really is a lot of fun. The community side of Shaped is obviously social, where joining and inviting your friends to shapes really stimulates a runner. And looking back at the route you ran and seeing it as part of a bigger picture (shape) makes you feel good and is a reward by itself.</p>
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>Features</h2>
    <p>The Shaped concept app same a couple of unique features and integrations that deserve highlighting.</p>
    
    <h3>Community</h3>
    <p>The community is a major part of Shaped. Tapping the globe from anywhere in the app brings you right to it. On the main community page you&rsquo;ll find a list of what your friends have shaped, along with a short summary, their route highlighted on a shape and a fun personal sentence each. Instead of saying &ldquo;Frank ran 15 km in 1:55&rdquo;, it says &ldquo;Frank ran a page from a book&rdquo;, which makes it really fun and enjoyable to scroll through the list.</p>

    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-community.png" alt="Shaped community" />
    <figcaption>A friend&rsquo;s overview, the community page, and joining/inviting friends&rsquo; shapes.</figcaption>
    
    <p>Tapping a friend&rsquo;s item will show an overview of that run including the shape on a map and the total shape. You can even join your friend&rsquo;s shape here.</p>
    <p>At the top is a &ldquo;Global shapes&rdquo; button, which brings up a big map with all the shapes worldwide. Tapping one allows you to see more details and even join it.</p>
    
    <h3>Shapes</h3>
    <p>The shapes in the app are great opportunities for companies to join the community as well. Companies like Coca Cola, Nike or McDonald&rsquo;s could introduce their own shapes for the community to run. For example the Red Cross could present a cancer awareness ribbon that all users around the globe could run on the same day. This would really send an amazing message.</p>
    <p>During holiday season, the app could suggest themed shapes like a bunny for Easter, Santa&rsquo;s hat with Christmas or Sinterklaas&rsquo; meiter in December 5th.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-stakeholders.svg" alt="Stakeholders RunKeeper, Health Graph API and TomTom" />
    
    <h3>Intelligence and Integration</h3>
    <p>Shaped is tightly integrated with <a href="http://runkeeper.com/">RunKeeper</a> and the <a href="http://runkeeper.com/developer/healthgraph/">Health Graph API</a> to sync all your workouts and friends, and get insight into your previous workouts and performances.</p>
    <p>If a runner selects a duration (time) to run, instead of a distance, the app will analyse his previous runs to get a distance he might be running in that timeframe. This historical data is an example of the integration with RunKeeper and the Health Graph API.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-integration.png" alt="Shaped community" />
    <figcaption>Syncs friends and workouts with RunKeeper. Uses historical health and workout data through Health Graph API to make shapes. Navigation and route planning are powered by TomTom.</figcaption>
    
    <h3>Navigation</h3>
    <p>Routes are calculated based on the user&rsquo;s location using GPS, the selected (or calculated) distance and of course the selected shape. Calculations are done using TomTom&rsquo;s routing API by cross referencing intermediate points of the shape with the map and planning routes between those. It will also give runners visual and voice directions so they can concentrate on their workout.</p>
    <p>After the workout is finished or stopped, the runner is presented with an overview of the run with some statistics of his/her workout and of course the travelled route and how good he/she contributed to the total shaped, which is quite rewarding. From this overview, the user can invite friends to contribute to the shape. </p>
    <video loop autoplay webkit-playsinline>
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/shaped-logo-animation.mp4"  type="video/mp4; codecs=avc1.42E01E,mp4a.40.2">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/shaped-logo-animation.webm" type="video/webm; codecs=vp8,vorbis">
        <source src="http://lex.test/vids/shaped-logo-animation.ogv"  type="video/ogg; codecs=theora,vorbis">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>    
</div>

<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>The Assignment</h2>
    <p>Design a product for savoring, that what <a href="#more">the assignment</a> wrote.</p>

    <h3>Savoring</h3>
    <blockquote>
    <p>People seem fairly good at seeking short moments of positive delight, however rather poor at enjoying joy in a lasting way. The initial pleasure, pride, or affection once experienced eventually fades because people adapt to a positive change and consequently take it for granted. This is detrimental for maintaining an increased level of happiness and calls for a new way of thinking and interacting in our environment: paying attention to and appreciating a positive experience (i.e. savoring) can slow down the process of adaptation and thereby maximize and prolong a happiness benefit.</p>
    </blockquote>    

    <h3>Insights and Ideation</h3>
    <p>In the exploration phase I conducted an online survey among runners. I learned that most runners run in the evening and about 3 times a week. My main insight was that running has a barrier of entry, but is fun afterwards. This occurs both on running as a whole as well as with each individual run. Also, about 37% of the runners do some form of preparation, and all of those see a positive effect on their performance.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-brainstorm.png" alt="Brainstorm" />
    <figcaption>Answering "how-to's" to generate ideas</figcaption>
    <p>I also gained some ideas on how to motivate and prepare people and how to create anticipation thanks to a brainstorm session with interested students. I found that greeting runners gives them a real boost and that sleeping in running gear removes a barrier to run in the morning (I tried). I also had a prototyping workshop, which gave me insights in how sending reminders, tasks and rewards to runners before a workout influenced their behavior.</p>
</div>
    



<div class="contentBlock">
    <h2>Design and Prototype</h2>
    <p>Shaped is designed specifically for iOS 7 and the iPhone 5. It uses the clean and simple design elements from iOS 7 like thin hairlines and white spaces, but also the advanced hierarchies and blur effects.</p>
    <img src="http://lex.test/img/portfolio/shaped-selection.png" alt="Selecting shapes in Shaped " />
    <figcaption>Shape selection in Shaped.</figcaption>
    <p>For my final presentation and prototyping the app, I made vector images of all the possible screens. I connected them together in <a href="https://www.flinto.com">Flinto</a> to make a testable and presentable prototype.</p>
</div><hr><ul><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-info-circle"></i><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&category=app" title="View App projects">App</a> for <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=runkeeper" title="View projects for RunKeeper">RunKeeper</a></span>, <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=diopd" title="View projects for Delft Institute of Positive Design">Delft Institute of Positive Design</a></span>, and <span class="ownName"><a href="http://lex.test/filter/&client=tudelft" title="View projects for TU Delft">TU Delft</a></span></span> from
                         <a href="http://lex.test/filter/&year=2014" title="View projects from 2014">2014</a>.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-users"></i>Individual project focusing on conceptualising, designing and video editing.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-graduation-cap"></i><b>Course</b>: Exploring Interactions.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-file-text"></i><b>Assignment</b>: How can design support savoring in our personal lives? There are multiple possibilities to focus on in the design solution: for instance, savoring can span from attending to positive feelings in the present, to reminiscing about the past and anticipating the future. Furthermore, the target of savoring can be an event, circumstance, other person, object, or a human-product interaction as such.</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-thumbs-up"></i><b>Acknowledgments</b>: <ul>
<li>Shaped was used as a design example in the paper <a href="http://studiolab.ide.tudelft.nl/diopd/library/enjoying-joy-a-process-based-approach-to-design-for-prolonged-pleasure/">Enjoying Joy. A Process-Based Approach to Design for Prolonged Pleasure.</a> by <span style="white-space: nowrap;">Dr.-Ing. Anna E. Pohlmeyer</span> (2014).</li>
<li>Shaped was exhibited at the <a href="http://www.ecpp2014.nl">7th European Conference on Positive Psychology</a> in Amsterdam, the Netherlands (2014).</li>
</ul></li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-calendar" title="Monday, 15 December 2014 at 13:13 Europe/Amsterdam time"></i>Posted on <time datetime="2014-12-15 13:13:00" pubdate>Monday, 15 December 2014</time>, last updated on 18 June 2016</li><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-question-circle"></i>Want to know more about Shaped? <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:hello@lexpostma.me?subject=Shaped" title="Email Lex">email me</a>.</span></li></ul>]]></description>
			</item>
    </channel>
</rss>